<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Themes on Hugo: A Fast and Flexible Website Generator</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/themes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Themes on Hugo: A Fast and Flexible Website Generator</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 10:03:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/themes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Themes Overview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/themes/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 10:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/themes/overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo provides a robust theming system which is simple, yet capable of producing
even the most complicated websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hugo community has created &lt;a href=&#34;//themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;a wide variety of beautiful themes&lt;/a&gt;, as demoed at &lt;a href=&#34;//themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;themes.gohugo.io&lt;/a&gt;,
ready for using in your own site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo themes have been designed to be the perfect balance between
simplicity and functionality. Hugo themes are powered by the excellent
Go template library. If you are new to Go templates, see our &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/templates/go-templates/&#34;&gt;primer on
Go templates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo themes support all modern features you come to expect. They are
structured in such a way to eliminate code duplication. Themes are also
designed to be very easy to customize while retaining the ability to
maintain upgradeability as the upstream theme changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo currently doesn’t ship with a “default” theme, allowing the user to
pick whichever theme best suits their project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you will find Hugo themes perfect for your site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Themes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/themes/installing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 10:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/themes/installing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Community-contributed &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo themes&lt;/a&gt;, showcased
at &lt;a href=&#34;//themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;themes.gohugo.io&lt;/a&gt;, are hosted in a centralized
GitHub repository.  The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugoThemes&#34;&gt;Hugo Themes Repo&lt;/a&gt;
itself at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugoThemes&#34;&gt;github.com/spf13/hugoThemes&lt;/a&gt; is
really a meta repository which contains pointers to set of contributed themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-all-themes:3cef5cab5612f8cc3d40c6e13331783b&#34;&gt;Installing all themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to install all of the available Hugo themes, simply
clone the entire repository from within your working directory:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ git clone --recursive https://github.com/spf13/hugoThemes.git themes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-a-specific-theme:3cef5cab5612f8cc3d40c6e13331783b&#34;&gt;Installing a specific theme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mkdir themes
$ cd themes
$ git clone URL_TO_THEME
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a Theme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/themes/usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 10:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/themes/usage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please make certain you have installed the themes you want to use in the
&lt;code&gt;/themes&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use a theme for a site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo -t ThemeName
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;ThemeName&lt;/em&gt; must match the name of the directory inside &lt;code&gt;/themes&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo will then apply the theme first, then apply anything that is in the local
directory. To learn more, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/themes/customizing/&#34;&gt;customizing themes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing a Theme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/themes/customizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 10:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/themes/customizing/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following are key concepts for Hugo site customization. Hugo permits you to &lt;strong&gt;supplement or override&lt;/strong&gt; any theme template or static file, with files in your working directory.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When you use a theme cloned from its git repository, you do not edit the theme&amp;rsquo;s files directly. Rather, you override them as per the following:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;replace-static-files:0b8b0e4b5279f6824ca9414b485f6c4a&#34;&gt;Replace Static Files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For including a different file than what the theme ships with. For example, if you would like to use a more recent version of jQuery than what the theme happens to include, simply place an identically-named file in the same relative location but in your working directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if the theme has jQuery 1.6 in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/themes/themename/static/js/jquery.min.js
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; you would simply place your file in the same relative path, but in the root of your working folder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/static/js/jquery.min.js
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;replace-a-single-template-file:0b8b0e4b5279f6824ca9414b485f6c4a&#34;&gt;Replace a single template file&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anytime Hugo looks for a matching template, it will first check the working directory before looking in the theme directory. If you would like to modify a template, simply create that template in your local &lt;code&gt;layouts&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/templates/overview/&#34;&gt;template documentation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;each different template type explains the rules it uses to determine which template to use&lt;/em&gt;. Read and understand these rules carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially helpful when the theme creator used &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/templates/partials/&#34;&gt;partial templates&lt;/a&gt;. These partial templates are perfect for easy injection into the theme with minimal maintenance to ensure future compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/themes/themename/layouts/_default/single.html
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; would be overridden by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/layouts/_default/single.html
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: This only works for templates that Hugo &amp;ldquo;knows about&amp;rdquo; (that follow its convention for folder structure and naming). If the theme imports template files in a creatively-named directory, Hugo won’t know to look for the local &lt;code&gt;/layouts&lt;/code&gt; first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;replace-an-archetype:0b8b0e4b5279f6824ca9414b485f6c4a&#34;&gt;Replace an archetype&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the archetype that ships with the theme for a given content type (or all content types) doesn’t fit with how you are using the theme, feel free to copy it to your &lt;code&gt;/archetypes&lt;/code&gt; directory and make modifications as you see fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beware-of-the-default:0b8b0e4b5279f6824ca9414b485f6c4a&#34;&gt;Beware of the default&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Default&lt;/strong&gt; is a very powerful force in Hugo, especially as it pertains to overwriting theme files. If a default is located in the local archetype directory or &lt;code&gt;/layouts/_default/&lt;/code&gt; directory, it will be used instead of any of the similar files in the theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is usually better to override specific files rather than using the default in your working directory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Theme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/themes/creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 10:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/themes/creation/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hugo has the ability to create a new theme in your themes directory for you
using the &lt;code&gt;hugo new&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new theme [name]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command will initialize all of the files and directories a basic theme
would need. Hugo themes are written in the Go template language. If you are new
to Go, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/layout/go-templates/&#34;&gt;Go template primer&lt;/a&gt; will help you get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;theme-components:e2f4d16490492eca6fd5eb1f0df60240&#34;&gt;Theme Components&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A theme consists of templates and static assets such as javascript and css
files. Themes can also optionally provide &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/content/archetypes/&#34;&gt;archetypes&lt;/a&gt;
which are archetypal content types used by the &lt;code&gt;hugo new&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;layouts:e2f4d16490492eca6fd5eb1f0df60240&#34;&gt;Layouts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo is built around the concept that things should be as simple as possible.
Fundamentally website content is displayed in two different ways, a single
piece of content and a list of content items. With Hugo a theme layout starts
with the defaults. As additional layouts are defined they are used for the
content type or section they apply to. This keeps layouts simple, but permits
a large amount of flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;single-content:e2f4d16490492eca6fd5eb1f0df60240&#34;&gt;Single Content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default single file layout is located at &lt;code&gt;layouts/_default/single.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;list-of-contents:e2f4d16490492eca6fd5eb1f0df60240&#34;&gt;List of Contents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default list file layout is located at &lt;code&gt;layouts/_default/list.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;partial-templates:e2f4d16490492eca6fd5eb1f0df60240&#34;&gt;Partial Templates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theme creators should liberally use &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/templates/partials/&#34;&gt;partial templates&lt;/a&gt;
throughout their theme files. Not only is a good DRY practice to include shared
code, but partials are a special template type that enables the themes end user
to be able to overwrite just a small piece of a file or inject code into the
theme from their local /layouts. These partial templates are perfect for easy
injection into the theme with minimal maintenance to ensure future
compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;static:e2f4d16490492eca6fd5eb1f0df60240&#34;&gt;Static&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything in the static directory will be copied directly into the final site
when rendered. No structure is provided here to enable complete freedom. It is
common to organize the static content into:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/css
/js
/img
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual structure is entirely up to you, the theme creator, on how you would like to organize your files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;archetypes:e2f4d16490492eca6fd5eb1f0df60240&#34;&gt;Archetypes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your theme makes use of specific keys in the front matter, it is a good idea
to provide an archetype for each content type you have. Archetypes follow the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/content/archetypes/&#34;&gt;guidelines provided&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;generator-meta-tag:e2f4d16490492eca6fd5eb1f0df60240&#34;&gt;Generator meta tag&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a growing community around Hugo we recommend theme creators to include the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/templates/variables/#hugo-variables:2b8b8ac4006be88c769f5e3fd99b009a&#34;&gt;Generator meta tag&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;code&gt;.Hugo.Generator&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; of your HTML code. The output  might looks like &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;generator&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;Hugo 0.13&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and helps us to analyse the usage and popularity of Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>